# ROBIN **SHRESTHA**

robinshrestha.maple@gmail.com

- **4** 613-796-1810
- ¶ 117 Thistledown Court, Nepean, Ottawa, ON
- nobinshrestha12? tab=repositories

Full Stack Web Developer with passion for code and more than a year of experience in Web applications and software development. Demonstrated proficiency in software development skills and research skills to find the solutions to the problems. Delivered high quality results in fast paced environment within project time framework.

### Skills

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, XML,Bootstrap, React, Node.js, Express, SQL Server, Mongo DB

#### **TESTING**

Cypress, Unit Tests

### INTEGRATED DEVELOPMENT(IDE)

Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, PyCharm, Android Studio, Visual Studio 2017

### OFFICE TOOLS

Mac OS, Windows, Linux - Ubuntu

### **OPERATING SYSTEM USAGE**

Mac OS, Windows, Linux - Ubuntu

### **Projects**

Interview Scheduler May 2022 to June 2022

With this application, a student can create, edit and delete interview appointments. It uses React, custom hooks, PostgreSQL database. The application to API server over HTTP by JSON format. The development follows the Test Driven Developmentindividual component testing and End-to-End testing.

Lighthouse BNB Apr. 2022 to May 2022

A database application project developed as a part of Lighthouse Labs Web development course.

**Twitter Project** Mar. 2022 to Mar. 2022

Tweeter is a single page app built with HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, AJAX, Express with tweeting funtionality.

TinvApp Feb. 2022 to Feb. 2022

TinyApp is a full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs like bit.ly website do. This project has an HTTP Server that handles requests from browser(client).

Oasis website July 2021 to Dec. 2021

Project going on Oasis website.

## Education

Lighthouse Labs, Toronto 2021 to Current Diploma in Web Development

Algonquin College, Ottawa 2017 to 2019 Diploma in Computer Programming 2019

Tribhuwan University 2011 to 2013

Bachelor of Business Studies

Modern React with Redux 2021(Udemy)

Node with React: Full Stack Web Development 2021(Udemy)

Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp 2021(Udemy)

Agile Scrum Training for Computer Programming 2018(CRA)

# **Employment**

### Oasis Non-Profit Project work, Ottawa

Ottawa 2022 to 2022

Freelance Web Developer

- Developed Oasis website for a non-profit organization using react-bootstrap, react, node.js. and Visual Studio Code.
- Designed different pages, added webpage language support (localization) and used Json, JavaScript, React-Bootstrap, React Router, React, Hooks, Redux, Node.js and MongoDB.

#### Visioneer Canada Inc. Ottawa

QA Engineer

2019 to 2020

- Reviewed quality documents and designed network documents
- Created comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases
- Used Microsoft Excel and Word for testing the window scanner application in various versions of Windows and Mac computers
- Created various networks and tested the application and recorded in OneNote
- Assisted in application development for Scanners using C# in Visual Studio 2017.

### Canada Revenue Agency, Government of Canada, Ottawa

Software Developer/Analyst Coop/ Internship

Sept. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Assisted in developmment of Integras Corporate Software of Canada Revenue Agency
- Used Java, XML and Java Swing coding languages and developed Gui applications
- Developed Data input validation techniques
- Completed various testings
- Got Scrum agile training

### Nokia Alcatel-Lucent - Ottawa, Kanata

Software Developer Coop/ Internship

May 2018 to Aug. 2018

- Developed a software Application for Nokia Pre-Sales Department
- Used Visual Basic programming language, SharePoint Server Lists, Microsoft Access
- Developed new techniques for Jira Application Data to be exported as excel files and imported to the
- Developed tracking mechanism for users and their data input from SharePoint online

# Volunteering

Knights of Columbus - current

Volunteered in Pinecrest Food Bank and as Office support staff. 2017